okay here we go we're gonna do the same
meditation this yesterday okay and this
is the one I'd like you to focus on to
the end tomorrow okay at the end of
class remind me there's a five minute
meditation I want to teach you okay
then your eyes are closed lightly not
too hard and maybe you're looking up
just a little bit over the horizon
your hands are soft and you have a small
Mona Lisa smile shoulders are pushed
back a little bit the chest is coming
out that means maybe your hands come
back on your legs a little bit so maybe
you're not touching your knees try to
remember not to wrinkle your forehead
keep it loose and the stomach is
slightly pulled in then come to the
sound of the air conditioner which is
easy if you're in your retreat cabin
there will be small noises outside birds
and maybe small noises inside
glue your mind to the cell see if you
can get that feeling your mind is stuck
to the sound like glue other thoughts
come other memories come other plans
come and you ignore them because your
mind is stuck to the air-conditioning
some as you start to meditate once in a
while check your forehead fingers mouth
eyes are they getting tight keep them
loose and relaxed the back is totally
straight you can check that back go
forward a little bit go back a little
bit go to the left a little bit go to
the right a little bit and find the
center where your back is stacked like a
stack of coins so slightly forward
slightly back find the middle point
if you have trouble concentrating
sometimes it helps me to focus on the
spot
not exactly between the eyebrows but go
up a little bit maybe centimeter and
then go into the head below the skull
and there's a sweet spot it's a small
chakra and it helps you focus your mind
so you can experiment with that the main
goal of your meditation especially these
two days feel free to experiment you
have to try many different things to
find the one that's best for you you are
different from everybody else in this
room so you need to experiment different
things different ways of sitting
different ways of breathing and if you
have trouble focusing you might try
bringing the mind to the forehead into
the forehead a little bit above the spot
between the eyebrows not too deep into
the forehead maybe just below the bone
you
now please bring your mind to your
heartbeat
my dear hobby leave the air-conditioner
behind it's difficult when they are
conditioner is loud but like all the
problems in your life it will make you
stronger if you try
now please come into the heart into a
beautiful meditation room inside the
heart lots of sunlight
into an inner chamber inside the heart
the heartbeat sounds very far away still
lots of sunlight
you see a small crystal of sugar and
focus your mind like a laser and put it
inside when you reach there again
there's a comfortable meditation room
with lots of sunlight but tiny tiny tiny
almost lost in the other objects of this
world one tiny grain of sugar near
inside
you
now your mind becomes as wide as the
Pacific Ocean very deep very very wide
as wide as the world and very calm very
peaceful spread your mind inside the
sugar crystals
include the sky the sky stretching even
farther up and is still including the
ocean
you
now turn the mind off still that's why
that's the ocean in the sky but try to
stop their thoughts in the mind make the
mind completely quiet
you
now our thoughts come in the mind just
let them float ignore them let them fade
away no tension in the mind no effort
now this in value teacher to come in sit
with you choose one of the teachers who
especially you have a feeling that they
care for you a lot they love you a lot
their whole appearance is very happy to
see you and care cares a lot about you
and your happiness wants to help you
then that's going to
to our past life try to imagine time in
a place when you were taking care of
perhaps a student of yours you were the
teacher and you had a student that you
really cared about them and you spent a
lot of time trying to help them teach
them try to imagine the circumstances
where were you what country what century
what did you look like what did they
look like when you were together what
did that look like
use your imagination have fun don't get
too serious don't get type
now imagine in the evening you're
meditating your student has gone home
and you are doing tomlin for your
student some kind of obstacle or
inability to learn and you are focusing
on none and you are doing tonin on them
so try to imagine some kind of
difficulty your student might have you
are meditating at home hundreds of years
ago you're doing tunnel meant for your
student who already went home what kind
of problem did he have
and imagine that problem as a black
smoke flowing from their limbs to their
heart collecting in their heart some
kind of very unpleasant black smoke
bring it all from their body from all
over their body bring it to their heart
now look in your own heart and prepare a
place to destroy that smoker beautiful
pink Lotus fragrant perfect shape very
beautiful very bright
you
in the middle of the Lada Caesar diamond
like the one in the meditation ring a
raw diamond very powerful the lordís
represents your love the diamond
represents your wisdom the Guardino
wisdom of emptiness
get it ready for the smoke
then we're going to breathe in the smoke
imagine each time you take a in breath
that breath air is coming into your left
nostril focus on your left nostril air
is coming in each time you take a breath
in we can't exactly control where the
which nostril the breath comes in but
imagine it's coming into the left and in
time it will come into the land if you
have trouble breathing to your nose you
have a cold or you can breathe through
your mouth but imagine is coming to the
left nostril in and all the way
down your spine to your heart
now let's bring the smoke in each time
you breathe in through the left nostril
the smoke in their heart the blackness
starts to come up through the right
nostril like you're pumping it out of
their heart with your breath
maybe your legs are hurting now maybe
you tired you're getting tired but if
you want to be a good meditator you have
to learn to ignore that you're tired or
something's hurting don't worry about it
it's it will pass focus on your
meditation the blackness comes to just
in front of your nose it's ready to come
into the left nostril we're going to
take one breath in the block this will
travel down the left side you can feel
it coming down through you're close to
your spine and then it will hit the
diamond and there will be a bright flash
of light like a photograph camera we'll
do it on the count of three together
imagine the blackness in front of your
left nostril one two and three
immediately comes down immediately
disjoin bright flash of life and your
student is already feeling better in
their home they are alone in their home
but suddenly they feel more relaxed the
problem they had is disappeared somehow
they don't really know why but they feel
much better
small smoke leftover from the darkness
like cigarette smoke gray thin we can
send it out of our right nostril clear
it out then gently we'll push some
golden light out of our right nostril
into the left nostril of our student
give them comfort and confidence
happiness warmth affection and care for
them in their own heart cross a
beautiful lotus and a diamond rod
diamond enjoy how they feel comfort
confidence beauty
come back to here teacher your own
teacher understand this is why you see
the love it was because you gave love
and long ago you planted seeds in your
domain and that's why you're seeing this
love and care about you that the teacher
has asked the teacher to come into your
heart and stay in your heart help you
during these two days of silence and
meditation please keep me silent not
just physically but in my mind stay with
me in my heart when I need you please
help me three-five
breath out Golden Lion to the world
around us Diamond Mountain is just a
small part of this world
we sent golden light out could karma
this meditation to help people around
the world then you can slowly open your
eyes take a good stretch drink something
you guys did good it was very quiet
either you were asleep or you were
meditating